Maybe one surprising thing was something
what we tested particularly in Asia. It
was actually in Japan. It was like a
long scrolling pay wall with a lot of
information like there was lots of
social proof reviews. There was like a
good comparison between the free tier
and the pro tier. And that design
actually worked incredibly well in Japan
driving I think 20% lift in revenue. But
actually the same design kind of failed
in the US. actually in the US more sort
of kind of easy to read or more kind of
cleaner design with like a slider and
the videos in the background and just
very punchy messages work much better
actually than the sort of very in-depth
and very descriptive design for Asia.
Hello, I'm your host David Bernard.
Today's conversation is shorter than
usual and will be featured in Revenue
Cat state of subscription apps report.
Each episode in this series will explore
one crucial topic and share actionable
insights from top subscription app
operators. With me today, Michael Paris,
senior growth product manager at Mojo.
On the podcast, I talked with Michael
about the experiments behind Mojo's 60%
lift in average revenue per user, why a
winning payw wall in Japan completely
failed in the US, and why not relying on
day one for most of your revenue is
actually a strength. Hey, Michael,
thanks so much for joining me on the
podcast today.
>> Hey, thanks for having me. you wrote a
blog post uh on the revenue cap blog a
while back about how Mojo increased
average revenue per user 60% in five
months and I've been wanting to have you
on since reading that blog post because
there are so many little things in there
I think people could take away from and
not everybody's going to read the blog
post and it's kind of fun to kind of dig
deeper into the things behind what ended
up in the blog post. So let's start
there. What are the things that led to
that 60% increase in average revenue per
user? There was actually like a bunch of
experiments we did on mainly payable and
pricing and there were particularly
three experiments which kind of stood
out and and brought that pretty pretty
good lift in in Arpoo. One of them was
uh sort of like a yearly plan as a as a
default. So initially like on a pay wall
we've showed the yearly and monthly plan
next to each other on like the very
first screen very first of payroll
screen and then we've tried putting the
monthly plan under sort of like a view
all plans button so it wasn't really
visible on the first glance and that
really helped drive uh yearly plan
adoption a lot like I think like a 15 or
20% percentage point so that helped a
lot actually increasing the new revenue
obviously or anything else that you that
was part of that that you think really
drove that success or you think it just
like I mean a lot of people experiment
with this but for some people it does
seem to work where it's like the you
know the yearly plan is listed with a
monthly amount and then the monthly plan
is listed at a much higher amount. Did
you did y'all test that at all of like
having the monthly plan maybe like way
higher to where it makes the yearly plan
look even better or or uh yeah what won
in that?
>> Yeah. Yeah, we experiment with that as
well. Yeah. So what we've tried and
succeeded was actually sort of like a
monthly plan encoring. So we essentially
added like a small line next to our sort
of yearly plan which says like that that
price is equivalent of I like 10 $10 $10
a month and that actually work very well
in comparison into yeah into that sort
of monthly plan which was obviously
higher the price was like 25 let's say.
So that kind of showed a yearly plan is
such a such a good deal comparing in the
in the cost. So that actually that
worked very well and and kind of
interesting. Wells that actually work
very well particularly in Latin America
uh in Brazil and Mexico.
>> That's super. Why do you think it
performed better in Latin American
countries in the US?
>> Yeah, because in the US it worked as
well but it was the increase was kind of
let's say a little bit less like it was
like 10% lift in your revenue and in
Latin America was way higher. was
actually about something like definitely
double digit was like 30 to 40
percentage and I think actually it
worked better there because that's sort
of just my hypothesis but I think
because the sort of like purchasing
power of those markets is lower than uh
than in the US typically. So people tend
to care more about like what's what's
the price there and they tend to
basically care more about yeah the cost
of the the apps and the subscriptions
they have and if they see that they this
doesn't cost much when they actually
look at it from let's say monthly
perspective like what they pay by month
it just kind of persuade them more and
triggered more the the conversion
behavior there. So yeah we were actually
super happy to have their net there and
online payroll. Had you already
experimented with lower prices in those
countries or was it a similar equivalent
price to US prices? No, we we did
actually was one just sort of another
kind of key experiment which drove the
60% increase in ARPU that we did a lot
of price testing as well and what some
of those actually include also Latin
America countries like typically yeah
Brazil and Mexico which were kind of the
top two geos from that region and so
we've actually lowered the price so we
we didn't have the equivalent of the US
prices that's something what I think
usually app store sort of suggests they
basically just do the exchange trade
right and then calculate. So no no we
didn't well we originally had that I
think in the past but then then we
obviously tested a bit lower prices and
it turned out it was actually better.
What was the key metric you were
tracking during this? Like what in
setting up all these experiments, you're
testing price, you're testing, you know,
pay wall layout, you're testing
placements, you know, do you have the
monthly and annual, you're you're
testing all these things. What was the
unifying metric you were looking at to
determine the success uh of those
experiments?
>> Yeah. So our sort of like a umbrella
metric for all those monization
experiments was the average revenue per
user in the first seven days. So this
kind of RPU RPU 7 7D 7D and yeah we've
like intentionally used it because we
well first of all we saw like more sort
of potential in optimizing the new
revenue rather than renewals and just
because that we wanted to shorten the
pay period. We wanted to optimize uh the
new revenue because of also sort of
supporting the user acquisition loop to
allow like higher spend etc. So we want
to drive new revenue as we saw that we
can actually scale that more and we can
actually compound that with the user
acquisition and get like more revenue in
in total and yeah so we that's why we
sort of chose the early average revenue
per user and specifically 7 day because
at that time we had 3-day trial so we
wanted to have the window to be long
enough to cover you know those three
four days and I think uh it was just 7
day I think mainly because actually
revenue get showed like one of these
arpoo like pre-default is actually
that's actually maybe the first one is
actually which was a available is is
7day so we choose like RP 7day just I
think because of that so and it actually
so it work pretty well yeah so basically
we optimize for the new revenue and as
you probably know and everyone else in
the app business like lots of new
revenue is coming from the very early
days like very first few days so it was
a good metric for just tracking making
new revenue.
>> Did you look back on some of those
experiments and see the impact on
retention? So, you know, did you
knowingly sacrifice some long-term
revenue for that quick return on ad
spend?
>> Typically, what where we look at
retention or at least some like a proxy
to retention like we use typically 7-day
cancellation rate as a sort of proxy for
retention rate or for renewal rate what
it could look like. And we typically
look at uh at this sort of proxy in when
we did like price testing because I I've
seen data that when you test in
different prices particularly like
higher prices usually you see sort of
higher cancellation rates and lower
granular rates with higher prices it's
kind of quite reasonable. So, and I
remember a couple of tests where we
actually like tested a different price
and the price actually mostly like a
higher price actually turned out to be
the winner on the new revenue. But when
we actually modeled having that new
price for a year long sort of
calculating a bit long long-term revenue
and we saw that we would actually
sacrifice in a long term mainly because
the renewal rates just dropped because
of the proxy 7day cancellation rate just
was way higher than for the baseline
price. So then we decided not to do that
and kept the original price and
sacrifice a bit of yeah less new revenue
but sort of having more new revenue in
the long term.
>> One of the things I talked about in
another one of these state subscription
apps podcast was how a lot of times
experiment results don't stack. So you
get a 10% win here and a 20% win there
and a 15% win here. And then then you
look at it at the end and you actually
haven't raised average revenue per user
by the the sum total of all those
experiments. You're kind of like getting
10% here but losing 5% there and getting
20% here but losing 10% there. What do
you feel like was the key to actually
stacking those successes? Were you
looking back as you tested each of those
to see if it had a negative impact on
some of your previous tests to be able
to generate that such a large increase
in average revenue per user
>> essentially like executed a bunch of
yeah pay one and price test and when
whenever we seen there is a sort of like
positive results whenever we've seen
yeah there is a there's a statistical
significant winner usually we've sort of
retested also in other markets so
usually let's say we've tested in the or
in the Europe and if it works there then
we've retested in other our key markets
to make sure that actually it will work
there and it happened a couple of times
that something we've only rolled out in
some of the markets and not in let's say
all over the world just because it we
haven't really seen a positive impact
sometimes also negative so we make sure
that particular change is actually
bringing additional incremental revenue
you know in all those key segments are
according the geo typically and if we
haven't seen that then we didn't roll it
out and then sort of in a high level
we've monitored the the RP 7day
typically actually in the revenue get
charge to essentially make sure that for
the new cohorts of users we actually
seen that lift uh in the AR of course
it's sometimes sort of hard to isolate
it from UA changes from other
externalities but and we tried to our
best to see if actually after rolling
out we're actually seeing that and and
yeah and then then yeah luckily we were
yeah we actually saw that yeah we
implemented changes and we seen that
it's actually going up the RPU and we
were sort of happy to happy to see that
and and kept that process keep going.
>> Uh were there any surprising results
like something that worked incredibly
well in Brazil but was terrible in the
US or something amazing in Europe that
failed in Latin America? Maybe one
surprising thing was uh something what
we tested particularly in Asia. It was
actually in Japan. It was like a long
scrolling pay wall with a lot of
information like there was lots of
social proof reviews. There was like a
good comparison between the free tier
and and the pro tier. And that design
actually worked incredibly well in Japan
driving I think 20% lift in revenue. But
actually the same design kind of failed
in the in the US. actually in the US
more sort of kind of easy to read or
more kind of cleaner design with like a
slider and the videos in the background
and just very punchy messages work much
better actually than the sort of very
in-depth and very descriptive design for
Asia.
>> Yeah, that's fascinating. I did want to
talk now about placements. So, you know,
of course, as with most subscription
apps these days, Mojo does show a payw
wall on onboarding, but I was surprised
to see the stats that that only 50%, and
I say only 50% because in the revenue
cat data, we see more like 80% of payers
across, you know, the entire
subscription industry happen in that
first day. So, what else have you done
to drive those conversions after the
that initial uh onboarding? Yeah, that
was actually that was actually the
number one thing which surprised me the
most when I actually joined Mojo. It was
my first sort of mobile first kind of
business job I've did that actually
there's so much actually revenue coming
from the very first day. But then I
learned actually it's very normal and
it's even like lower than just yeah most
apps do like 80%. And I think actually
the that the number like 50% is actually
it's actually a good signal that if the
app actually does that I think it's it's
a very good signal for the app that it
can actually drive a good revenue also
from existing users. It's it's likely
have a good retention and essentially a
lot of existing users and it's kind of
sounds to me like a really very healthy
sort of behavior and and and and signal.
There's a I think a couple of things I
think why Mojo has 50%. One is that the
free tier is, you know, is actually I
think it's pretty good also comparing
also to some other competitors. Actually
in the free tier you can actually can do
quite a lot. So it's not that restricted
like maybe some other ads. Uh there's a
lots of features which is actually
available in the free tier lots of
content. So that's one thing. So like
the let's say generosity of the free
tier which was intentional. The other
aspect is that we've run also like the
payw wall campaigns for existing users
which I think not a lot of maybe not
most of the apps actually do and I think
it's actually one of the kind of
underrated things which I think most of
the apps should do. So essentially is
running a payw wall campaign. So, so is
she triggering the pay wall in certain
behavior for existing users either as an
app open like we did in Mojo or after
some key behavior event like when you
yeah do something key in your app like I
don't know sharing something or whatever
the key kind of engagement event is. So
that payroll campaign actually drove I
think about 15% of new revenue from the
existing user base which is yeah just
pretty a lot and it's super simple to
set up and it wasn't really kind of
having any negative reviews on that from
the users. So it's kind of a no-brainer
to have that.
>> Yeah, that's surprising. So so free
users they open the app and immediately
see a pay wall.
>> Yeah, they hit a pay wall. Yeah. And
actually it worked. Yeah. I was and
quite a lot of users actually Yeah. It
actually drove a lot of revenue. Yeah.
Did you check churn and other things?
Like I I mean I guess that's the thing
is like you do always kind of trade off.
So maybe there was a little bit of churn
but then the additional revenue kind of
made up for that but any other things
you track like you said there were no
negative reviews which that that's
shocking to me. People seem to go out of
their way to like you complain about
things like that in the app store
reviews but support retention like any
any downsides to this payw wall on app
open. It was on the app open, but it was
I think the frequency is set to one pay
wall per week. So you don't actually
even if you open the app every day and a
couple of day couple multiple times a
day, you just essentially have that
payroll only being triggered once a week
essentially the frequency was pretty
low. So which also I think played some
role why users weren't complaining. But
I I specifically actually asked a
colleague from support and he didn't
really mention that user complaining. Uh
I did once like a quite thorough
analysis of all the reviews and try to
find like what users you know complain
about not really from that particular
reason but I was more interested like
what user like what I didn't like and I
actually haven't really seen any
specific negative about having a pay
wall a lot of times displayed etc. So
yeah, so actually it was a good thing
here for us.
>> It's surprising sometimes when people
are getting something for free, they
tolerate more than we assume sometimes,
you know, like uh I know a lot of games
and even some regular apps have full
screen interstitial ads. I mean,
Dualingo is actually a great example of
this. You know, they they do it very
tastefully, but they have a full screen
unskippable takeover ad after a lesson.
So, I think people do kind of
intuitively get the exchange of value
there of like, oh, I'm using this
completely for free. And I think you can
get away with it more if you're premium
tier is very generous, like you were
saying. And maybe that's kind of the
key. It's like if if your premium tier
sucks, one, you're probably not going to
get much retention anyway, so not many
people are going to see the app open pay
walls. And then two, like they feel like
they're, you know, pulling one over on
you or or, you know, getting something
getting, you know, they feel like
they're getting a lot of value. And so
when they see that that uh payw wall,
it's probably less offensive in those
kind of situations. So, but fascinating
how how well that worked.
>> 100%. Yeah, I really encourage everyone
to essentially Yeah, just try that. Just
say, "Yeah, test it, AB test it, just
measure it." And I think yeah, most of
all you will be surprised that the users
will not react the way how you kind of
offer fear they react. So it's uh I
definitely would recommend just trying
things out. The last thing I wanted to
touch on was experiment velocity. You
all did a lot of tests. H how do you
keep up with that? How do you isolate
variables? Yeah. How do you think about
testing velocity?
>> Oh yeah, that was it was I think super
important. And I actually think that
it's the kind of number one growth asset
as a yeah as everyone who actually wants
to optimize pay walls and pricing. If
you have good research, good
prioritization, if the velocity is I
think even kind of it's even maybe more
important because there's more shots you
take, there's essentially higher chance
you win. There's a shorter sort of
feedback loop, better learning cycle. So
it's it was a key and yeah I did a lot
of experiments and I think maybe the
number one thing which allowed me to do
that was having kind of a third party
payable platform allowed me to being
autonomous and and iterate fast and and
really kind of shorten the the cycle of
actually like coming up with experiment
developing it launching it from yeah
months or weeks to to to essentially
days. So that it was so kind of
important that I think without it I
would definitely wouldn't be able to get
that amount of experiments live in yeah
in that short time. That makes a tense
sense. And you know Mojo is a pretty big
app and you were doing a ton of user
acquisition. So you did have a lot of
users coming in to be able to do the
test on. But did you have a particular
testing velocity? like would you be
launching it on a weekly cadence or even
like 3 days and then wait for the data
to make a final decision but while
you're already kicked off another test?
It was more weekly or bi-weekly cadence
but what was also important to say that
we mostly run experiments. We typically
kind of broke down the audience the the
new users to sort of three buckets
according to GIO. It was like a US or
kind of US, Australia, Canada kind of
English, US English packet. Then there
was the Europeans and then there was
Latin America. And we typically had like
this streams of tests for each this
specific kind of geo bucket and we've
run tests in all of them three in
parallel and each test kind of lasted
usually one or two weeks because in
those three GE those are kind of this
three key geo segments we had and we
were able to get the statistically
significant results usually in those one
or two weeks for each of those buckets.
So we were able to to conduct
experiments there. I think a great way
to summarize this whole episode is you
should be testing a lot. If you're not,
you're leaving revenue on the table.
Again, it's just such a clear example
that you were able to increase average
revenue per user by 60% in 5 months.
That is such a huge win for the company
ability to acquire new users and then
you know over the long haul building
that subscriber base over time. So such
a fascinating lesson and thanks for for
sharing your insights today.
>> Thanks thanks again for having me David.
It was really yeah a pleasure to talk
with you.
>> Anything else you wanted to share as we
wrapped up?
>> I encourage folks if you want to learn
more about your payroll testing and
monetization just you follow me on
LinkedIn. I tend to share some of the
advices and experience there. So yeah
hopefully you can learn something more.
>> Awesome. We'll put a link to that in the
show notes. Thank you so much Michael
for joining me today. It was really fun.
>> Thanks a lot David.
>> Thanks so much for listening. If you
have a minute please leave a review in
your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.